LEAH BANKS

□ leahb_96@hotmail.co.uk
□ 07939 263 330
□ London

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/leahrbanks https://github.com/leahbanks https://leah-banks.netlify.app

PROFILE

I am a recent graduate of the industry-leading Northcoders bootcamp, where I gained proficiency in JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS and Node. I am a logical thinker with a background in Customer Happiness, Team Management and the arts, pursuing my first role in Software Development - a field that combines my professional knowledge of user experience, with my enthusiasm for creative problem solving and my passion for creating accessible and aesthetically-pleasing applications for users to enjoy.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Javascript, TypeScript

Front End: React, React Native, HTML,

Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Document Object

Model (DOM). Awareness of: SASS

Back End: Node.js, REST APIs, Express.js,

PostgreSQL, OAuth

Testing: Jest, SuperTest, Test Driven

Development (TDD)

Version Control: Git

Project Management/Design: Trello, Jira, Confluence, ReTool, Excalidraw, Canva, Figma

PROJECTS

Portfolio

https://leah-banks.netlify.app

A responsive mobile-first application and a collection of my recent projects.

NC News

https://nc-news-lb.netlify.app

NC News API

https://nc-news-81lq.onrender.com/api

Through the Fog

https://github.com/leahbanks/FE-through-the-fog

EDUCATION

University of Westminster

BA Fine Art Mixed Media First Class Honours

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Between September and November 2022, I undertook a career transition and self-taught basic Javascript in order to kickstart my career in Software Development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Northcoders

November 2022 - March 2023

- · Pair programming to write production-ready code front-end and back-end frameworks.
- Gained hands on experience with React, React Router, HTML5 and CSS3 to create front-end web applications from wireframes.
- Gained awareness of WCAG, PWAs and a mobile-first approach, using Lighthouse to improve accessibility.
- · Built a full-stack mobile application in a team, using agile methodologies to ensure efficiency and transparency.
- Used Express.js to build server endpoints and develop RESTful APIs using CRUD operations.
- Utilised Git for version control best practice.

Customer Happiness Team Leader

Oddbox

April 2022 - September 2022

- Managed and supported a team of 6 agents to meet weekly KPI targets, holding fortnightly and quarterly reviews.
- Proactively handled any tech issues that arose, alerting and working with the relevant teams to implement solutions and minimise impact on the customer.
- Worked closely with the Product team to relay feedback on the website, test new functionality and inform decisions on the user journey during the migration to a new subscription management system.
- Worked closely with the Tech team to manage the website's Al Chat Bot and optimise its performance.

Customer Happiness Executive

November 2022 - April 2022

Oddbox

- Addressed complaints and gueries with efficiency and empathy.
- Regularly surpassed weekly KPI targets (200 tickets solved).
- Managed and updated online FAQs to improve user experience and streamline customer contact.
- Safely managed customer data to conform to GDPR guidance.
- · Worked collaboratively within my own team and other teams using systems such as ReTool and Atlassian (Confluence and Jira).

Visitor Experience Assistant

Serpentine Galleries

April 2019 - November 2020

- · Acted as a first point of contact for all visitors and internal staff.
- Used creative eye and close attention to detail to design effective Visual Merchandising and drive sales.

Gallery Host

June 2018 - April 2019

Serpentine Galleries

· Developed public speaking skills by delivering exhibition tours and presentations to the public.

Further work experience is available upon request.